Moses Umogbai

mosesumogbai@gmail.com | (647) 554-4496 | Toronto, ON M5A 0V7 | website: mosesumogbai.com

Overview

Experienced Software Developer with working knowledge across multiple software stack(s) in agile environments with cutting-edge technologies, by engineering secure, accessible, and responsive mobile and web applications, achieving business goals

Skills

Programming: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, SASS/CSS3, jQuery, Axios, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Java, Python, Bash, Jest Test, Storybook, Lerna, AMPscript, Guide Template Language

State Management Patterns/Architecture: Experience with Model-View-Controller (MVC) / Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM), Flux, Redux, Redux Tool Kit, Redux Toolkit Query, REST APIs

Content Management System: Adobe Experience Manager (AEM), WordPress, Shopify Analytics & Personalization: Certona, Gigya, Salesforce Marketing Cloud (SFMC), Sumo Logic

Cloud technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, New Relic CI/CD tools & Others: Git, Rundeck, Bamboo, Ansible, Jenkins, Terraform, Docker

Experience

Canadian Tire Corporation | Toronto, ON React Front-end Developer / Product Engineering

Oct 2020 - Present

- Collaborated with onshore and offshore teams to migrate Canadian Tire and its subsidiaries' frontend from jQuery to React. Developed cart, checkout, and browsing features, resulting in a streamlined, shared codebase with reusable components across all sites increasing developer output and resulting in fast turnaround development cycles
- Implemented user transaction components, sign-in and registration functionalities, for Triangle (a subsidiary) as part of the initiative to revamp the frontend codebase architecture with React, thereby eliminating redundant code and improving code readability and reusability, resulting in approximately 30M revenue increase and better developer experience overall
- Developed Single Sign On (SSO) functionality that allows the user to sign in with the same credentials across multiple banners such as Canadian Tire, Party City, Marks, Atmosphere, and L'equipeur thereby increasing user retention by 20%
- Delivered Sales Alerts functionality on the BuyBox for all products allowing users to opt into alerts which in return generated an increase in sales and customer conversions by 10 to 15%

Android Mobile Application Developer / Mobile Technology

Feb 2020 - Sept 2020

- Contributed to wayfinding feature to help users to navigate stores with precision and ease
- Developed a new home screen as per design specifications improving user experience and personalization

DevOps Analyst / Cloud Operations & Automation

June 2019 - Jan 2020

- Created new relic dashboards based on specific rules to monitor and efficiently filter through superfluous logs while also tracking server utilization metrics
- Automated Operating System patching on servers keeping the machines updated with security fixes and critical bug fixes

Education

University of Toronto | Toronto, ON Certificate in Web Development using React

April 2021

Seneca College | Toronto, ON Degree in Computer Networking Systems Technology June 2018

University of Toronto | Toronto, ON

April 2016

Computer Science